Finding Aid for Kenneth Earl Peters collection, ca. 1900-1919
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kenneth Earl Peters collection ca. 1900-1919
Peters, Kenneth Earl, collector.
5 microfilm rolls
8992 Aa Microcopy
Student at the University of Michigan. Collected material relating to the Good Roads Movement in Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
These microfilm reels were donated by Kenneth E. Peters (donor no. 4495 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Kenneth Earl Peters, at the time this material was collected, was a doctoral student in history at the University of Michigan.
This collection consists of negative microfilm copies of records located at the National Archives and Records Administration and the Library of Congress. These records were used in Kenneth Earl Peters' doctoral dissertation "The Good-Roads Movement and the Michigan State Highway Department, 1905-1917."
Subjects:
Roads--Michigan.
- Post Office Department, Record Group 28
  (Originals at National Archives)
  - Division of Rural Mails, Entry 214, General Records, 1902-1934 (Reel 1)
    (Boxes 42-45. Arranged alphabetically by name of Michigan county (incomplete) Papers relate to the inspections made by Post Office Department (POD) prior to establishment of county-wide Rural Free Delivery Services (RFD))
  - Bureau of the Fourth Assistant Postmaster General, Division of Rural Mails
    - Records, 1902-1910 Entry 216, Forms, 1902-1910. 6 pages. (Reel 2)
  - Immediate Office of the Fourth Assistant Postmaster General.
    - Entry 184-General Records, 1902-1932
      - Box 62. 142 pp. (Reel 2)
      - Box 32. 287 pp. (Reel 2)
      - Box 38. 161 pp. (Reel 2)
    - Entry 185-Correspondence of James I. Blakslee, 1914-1920
      - Box 1. 41 pp. (Reel 2)
      - Box 2. 85 pp. (Reel 2)
      - Box 3. 48 pp. (Reel 2)
    - Entry 215-Records of the Division of Rural Mails, "Records relating to Acts Providing for Federal Aid to Post Roads, September 1912-March 1917"
      - Box 2. 97 pp. (Reel 2)
    - Entry 214-General Records, 1915-1934
      - Box 197. 32 pp. (Reel 2)
      - Box 193. 54 pp. (Reel 2)
- Secretary of Agriculture, Record Group 16
  - Secretary's Office, 1918 - incoming correspondence. Acc. 234, Drawer 237 (metal box). 39 pp. (Reel 3)
  - Secretary's Office-Alpha 63, carton 3. 125 pp. (Reel 3)
  - Roads-Michigan, 1918 TR-240 (green folder). 133 pp. (Reel 3)
  - Secretary's Office, 1918 - Incoming correspondence. "Roads" Acc. 234, Draver 238. 22 pp. (Reel 3)
- Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
  - William Howard Taft Papers, Series 6 (Reel 4)
    - File 1053 (Box 426)..1914-1918, 31 pp (Reel 4)
  - Woodrow Wilson Papers, Series 4
    - File 1, Box 1 "Department of Agriculture" 1914-1918, 24 pp (Reel 4)
    - File 791, Box 302 "National Highways Association", 9 pp (Reel 4)
    - File 361, Box 219 "Good Roads Agitation, 1913", 33 pp (Reel 4)
    - File 361, Box 219 "Good Roads Agitation, 1914", 11 pp. (Reel 4)
    - File 361, Box 220 "Good Roads Agitation, 1915", 3 pp (Reel 4)
    - File 361, Box 220 "Good Roads Agitation, 1916", 16 pp. (Reel 4)
    - File 361, Box 220 "Good Roads Agitation, 1917", 6 pp. (Reel 4)
    - File 361, Box 220 "Good Roads Agitation, 1918-1919", 37 pp. (Reel 4)
- Bureau of Public Roads, Record Group 30
  - Selected records relating to Michigan Roads and Roads in general, ca. 1900-1919. (Reel 4)